syntactically awesome stylesheets or sass is a language that can extend your
语法上很棒的样式表或sass 是一种可以用超能力扩展你的
css with super powers modern uis are extremely complex and if
css 的语言现代用户界面非常复杂，如果
you attempt to build one with plain css you'll find yourself repeating yourself
你尝试用普通 css 构建一个你会发现自己经常重复自己
often sas comes to the rescue by providing a compiler
sas 通过提供一个允许的编译
that allows us to write style sheets in a completely different language well two
器来拯救 我们用完全不同的语言编写样式表 两种
different languages to be exact the original
不同的语言 准确地说
indented syntax that you find in dot sass files removes the syntactic salt of
是您在点 sass 文件中找到的原始缩进语法删除了
semicolons and curly braces [Applause]
分号和花括号的语法盐[掌声]
[Music] but the more popular version is the
[音乐]但更流行的版本是
superset syntax that you find in scss files
您可以在此处的 scss 文件中找到超集语法，
here you can write regular css then extend it with additional bonus features
您可以编写常规 css，然后
as needed sas has been around for nearly 15 years
根据需要使用额外的额外功能对其进行扩展sas 已经存在了近 15 年
and one of its original killer features was variables
，其原始杀手功能之一是变量
use a dollar sign to name a variable then reference it somewhere else in your
使用美元符号命名变量然后引用 它现在在你的代码中的其他地方，
code now if that value ever changes you only
如果该值发生变化，你只
have to update one line of code css introduced its own native variables a
需要更新一行代码 css引入了它自己的本机
few years ago but the advantages don't stop there
几年前的变量，但优势并不止于此，第二个
killer feature number two is nesting in many cases
杀手级功能是嵌套在许多情况下，
classes are used as name spaces which means they're often duplicated over and
类被用作名称空间，这意味着它们经常一遍
over again we can avoid this duplication by nesting styles inside the parent by
又一遍地重复我们可以通过在父级中嵌套样式来避免这种重复
default these classes will apply to descendant elements or
默认情况下，这些类将应用于后代元素，或者
they can be applied to a direct sibling by using the ampersand which
它们可以通过使用 & 符号应用于直接同级元素，它
itself is a tool that tells sas to combine the parent selector with the
本身是一种告诉 sas将父选择器与
nested child selector now one other issue with css is that
嵌套子选择器组合的工具，现在 css 的另一个问题是
you'll often find yourself including a similar group of styles on multiple
你' 您经常会发现自己在多个类中包含一组相似的样式
classes mix-ins allow you to encapsulate a group of styles
mix-ins 允许您封装一组样式，
then apply those styles anywhere in your code using the include keyword
然后使用 include 关键字在代码中的任何位置应用这些样式
mixons can also take arguments to create a large number of similar classes
mixons 也可以带参数以编程方式创建大量相似的类
programmatically like a bunch of different colored
比如一堆不同颜色的
buttons for example in addition sas provides a whole suite of tools to
按钮，另外sas 提供了一整套工具来
help you write more programmatic code use if or else in a mixin for
帮助你编写更多的程序化代码在 mixin 中使用 if 或 else 用于
conditional logic or create an array of values with a variable then loop over
条件逻辑，或者使用变量创建一个值数组，然后
them with each and you might even extract all this
用每个循环遍历它们，您甚至可以将所有这些
logic into a reusable function or sas might already have a built-in
逻辑提取到可重用函数中，或者 sas 可能已经
function for you ready to go if you need to adjust a color you can
为您准备好了内置函数如果您需要调整颜色，您可以
use the lighten or darken functions to adjust a color by a predictable value
使用变亮或变暗功能
when you're finished building a beautiful ui
在完成构建漂亮的
the compiler will take your code and convert it into valid css that can run
ui 后将颜色调整为可预测的值，编译器将获取您的代码并将其转换为可以运行的有效 css
in the browser this has been sas in 100 seconds but
浏览器在 100 秒内完成了 sas，但
before you go here's one more bonus pro tip when working with nested code it can
在您使用嵌套代码时，这里还有一个额外的专业提示，
sometimes be hard to figure out exactly which set of braces you're
有时很难确定您在 vs 代码中到底是哪组大括号
inside of in vs code enable the bracket pair colorizer extension to give each
启用括号对着色器 扩展以赋予
set of braces their own unique color make sure to hit the like button if you
每组牙套自己独特的颜色如果您
want to see more short videos like this thanks for watching and i will see you
想观看更多这样的短片，请确保点击“喜欢”按钮感谢收看，我会
in the next one
在下一个